<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.orchard.cc/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.orchard.cc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-07-11T18:50:53+00:00</updated><id>https://www.orchard.cc/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Orchard</title><subtitle>A way to share the Word of God to those who happen upon this place.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Send Word</title><link href="https://www.orchard.cc/posts/life/2021/07/10/send-word" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Send Word" /><published>2021-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.orchard.cc/posts/life/2021/07/10/send-word</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.orchard.cc/posts/life/2021/07/10/send-word">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Behold, about this time tomorrow, I will send a very heavy hail, such as has
not been seen in Egypt from the day it was founded until now. So now, send word,
bring your livestock and whatever you have in the field to safety. Every person
and animal that is found in the field and is not brought home, when the hail
comes down on them, will die. &lt;cite&gt;Exodus 9:18-19 NASB&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pharoah was told in advance about what was to come. Pharaoh could have ignored
this warning because of lack of belief in the words that he was told. Likewise,
Pharoah could have decided to not say anything to those who were still in the
field because of indifference toward their lives. Pharoah could have thought to
himself, “As long as I survive what is to come, that is all that matters. What
happens to other people is not my concern.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, some time before he was forewarned about the devastating hail that was
to come, Pharaoh was told in advance about a plague that will fall upon the land
of Egypt. The Lord said to Pharoah: If you refuse to let them go and continue to
hold them back, the hand of the Lord will bring a terrible plague on your
livestock in the field—on your horses, donkeys and camels and on your cattle,
sheep and goats (Exodus 9:2-3,5 NIV). Pharoah may not have bothered to warn
others of the pestilence that was to come. As such, when the Lord did just as he
had said the next morning, all the livestock of the Egyptians died (Exodus 9:6).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like Pharoah, you may know about what is to come. And like Pharoah, you may
decide to not say anything to those (unbelievers) who are still in the field
because of indifference to their lives. Like Pharoah, you may think, “As long
as my life is secure, that is all that matters. Whatever happens to others is
not my concern.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that should not be! Instead, you should share the Word of God to others so
that they may come to believe in Jesus Christ. Of course, not everyone whom you
share the Word of God to shall believe you. Some shall come to believe in Jesus
Christ when you share the Word of God with them; others shall not. That is out
of your control. All you can do is share the Word of God to others and let them
decide on whether or not to believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that sense, it is not too different from what happened when Pharaoh sent word
to those in the field about the hail that was to come. Whoever feared the word
of the Lord among the servants of Pharaoh hurried his slaves and his livestock
into the houses, but whoever did not pay attention to the word of the Lord left
his slaves and his livestock in the field (Exodus 9:20-21 ESV). Some believed
and hurried their livestock to safety whilst others did not believe and left the
livestock out in the field. Each person in the field made their own choice on
what to do after hearing the word that Pharoah shared to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, send word! Share the Word of God to others; and they shall ultimately
decide whether or not to believe in Jesus Christ and secure eternal life in
heaven. God bless.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Life" /><category term="Life" /><category term="Death" /><summary type="html">Behold, about this time tomorrow, I will send a very heavy hail, such as has not been seen in Egypt from the day it was founded until now. So now, send word, bring your livestock and whatever you have in the field to safety. Every person and animal that is found in the field and is not brought home, when the hail comes down on them, will die. Exodus 9:18-19 NASB</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.orchard.cc/%7B%22path%22=%3Enil%7D" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.orchard.cc/%7B%22path%22=%3Enil%7D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Storms</title><link href="https://www.orchard.cc/posts/life/2020/09/23/storms" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Storms" /><published>2020-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.orchard.cc/posts/life/2020/09/23/storms</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.orchard.cc/posts/life/2020/09/23/storms">&lt;p&gt;As it was mentioned in the previous message, people can learn to live with the
fears and challenges in one’s life by avoiding to deal with them rather than
confronting them. But as it was mentioned in the previous post, Jesus can remove
the obstacles and challenges in your life that you live with and avoid
confronting because of fear. With Jesus, you do not have to fear the challenges
/ obstacles that block your path. With Jesus, you can have the courage to
confront those obstacles. Because with Jesus, you can have confidence that those
challenges and obstacles that block your path shall go from you and perish and
be removed and cease to exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such a situation happened to Jesus’ disciples one day. One day he got into a
boat with his disciples, and he said to them, “Let us go across to the other
side of the lake.” So they set out, and as they sailed he fell asleep. And a
windstorm came down on the lake, and they were filling with water and were in
danger (Luke 8:22-23 ESV). Jesus’ disciples went sailing from their current
position in life to their destination across the lake. Whilst on their journey,
they encountered a stormy situation in their life. Like the people in the city
where the demon-possessed man lived in the tombs, Jesus’ disciples could have
learned to live with the stormy situation in their life. But they did not.
Instead, they went and woke him, saying, “Master, Master, we are perishing!” And
he awoke and rebuked the wind and the raging waves, and they ceased, and there
was a calm (Luke 8:24 ESV). Yes, the disciples told Jesus about the stormy
situation that they were in; and Jesus made the stormy situation in their life
cease to exist so that calm and peace was restored in their life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, you may be in the midst of a stormy situation in your life. Well, like
the disciples, you too may tell Jesus about the stormy situation in your life.
And like the storm that was rocking the boat that the disciples were in, Jesus
may also make the stormy situation in your life cease to exist so that there is
calm in your life. And of course Jesus can also calm the storms that exist in
society. Storms such as the Covid-19 pandemic. Storms such as the wildfires
raging across America. Storms such as the protests and counter-protests due to
systemic racial inequality. And the like. You can tell Jesus about these storms;
and Jesus can make them cease to exist so that calm and peace is restored in
your community, your city, society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can feel like Jesus is not there to help you through the storms. It can feel
like Jesus is asleep at the wheel while storms are raging all around you. That
may have been what Jesus disciples felt. Jesus was asleep whilst the storm was
raging all around them. Therefore, it may have felt like Jesus wouldn’t do
anything to help them whilst they were in the midst of the storms that they were
experiencing in life. Instead, it may have felt like Jesus would allow them to
succumb to the storms in their life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that is not true. What Jesus wanted His disciples to know was that there was
no reason to panic or be afraid whilst amidst the storms in their life. After He
made the storm cease to exist in their life, He said to them, “Where is your
faith?” And they were afraid, and they marveled, saying to one another, “Who
then is this, that he commands even winds and water, and they obey him?” (Luke
8:25 ESV) He was saying that you should not just be calm before the storm.
Instead, you should also be calm whilst you are amidst the storm because you
should have faith that Jesus is able and willing to make storms in your life
cease to exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, you do not need to panic or be fearful of the stormy situations that
exist in your life or your community. Whether it be the Covid-19 pandemic or the
wildfires or the racial tension raging in your community or some other storm in
your personal life, there is no need to panic or be afraid. Instead, you need to
have faith. Faith that Jesus will calm the storm in your life so that they cease
to exist. Just believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God bless.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Life" /><summary type="html">As it was mentioned in the previous message, people can learn to live with the fears and challenges in one’s life by avoiding to deal with them rather than confronting them. But as it was mentioned in the previous post, Jesus can remove the obstacles and challenges in your life that you live with and avoid confronting because of fear. With Jesus, you do not have to fear the challenges / obstacles that block your path. With Jesus, you can have the courage to confront those obstacles. Because with Jesus, you can have confidence that those challenges and obstacles that block your path shall go from you and perish and be removed and cease to exist.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/45976390/93406535-e4a6b900-f85d-11ea-8330-ca8eaed250ac.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/45976390/93406535-e4a6b900-f85d-11ea-8330-ca8eaed250ac.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Pass That Way</title><link href="https://www.orchard.cc/posts/life/2020/08/26/pass-that-way" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pass That Way" /><published>2020-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.orchard.cc/posts/life/2020/08/26/pass-that-way</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.orchard.cc/posts/life/2020/08/26/pass-that-way">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When He had come to the other side, to the country of the Gergesenes, there
met Him two demon-possessed men, coming out of the tombs, exceedingly fierce,
so that no one could pass that way. &lt;cite&gt;Matthew 8:28 NKJV&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were two demon-possessed men who lived amongst the tombs; and because of
this, no one could pass through that area lest they be met by them. Likewise,
there can be challenges / obstacles in one’s life that can prevent you from
going down a certain path in life. And instead of attempting to confront or
overcome those challenges and obstacles in one’s life, you instead try to avoid
them and learn to live with them. That is what the people of the Gergesenes did
with the two demon-possessed men. Rather than confronting and overcoming this
challenge / obstacle that lived amongst the tombs and prevented them from going
down the path, they avoided that area and learned to live with that obstacle in
life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From an individual standpoint, anything that you fear can stop you from going
down a certain path in life; and instead of trying to confront or overcome those
fears and obstacles, you learn to live with it and avoid things that may require
you to face your fears. For example, fears of social situations may cause you to
avoid going out and meeting new people. Fears of failure may cause you to not
even try to do something. And from a societal level, fear of racial profiling or
discrimination can cause certain people to refrain from going in or through
certain neighbourhoods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But fear not, for Jesus can remove those obstacles from your midst. That is what
happened with the two demon-possessed men. He said to them, “Go!” So they came
out [of the men] and went into the pigs, and the whole herd rushed down the
steep bank into the sea and died in the water (Matthew 8:32 AMP). Yes, Jesus
confronted and removed the obstacles that caused people to avoid that area.
Likewise, Jesus can also remove the obstacles and challenges in your life that
you live with and avoid confronting because of fear. With Jesus, you do not have
to fear the challenges / obstacles that block your path. With Jesus, you can
have the courage to confront those obstacles. Because with Jesus, you can have
confidence that those challenges and obstacles that block your path shall go
from you and perish and be removed and cease to exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And behold, the whole city came out to meet Jesus. And when they saw Him, they
begged Him to depart from their region. &lt;cite&gt;Matthew 8:34 NIV&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus was at the place where the two demon-possessed men used to terrorise the
people. And yet the whole city came out to meet Him. In other words, the people
went to the area that they used to avoid because of the two demon-possessed men.
Because of Jesus, the people were able to walk down the path that contained the
obstacle that they used to avoid. Likewise, Jesus can remove the roadblocks that
stop you from going down certain paths in life. And because of Jesus, you too
can go down paths that used to contain obstacles that you used to avoid. Just
believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God bless.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Life" /><summary type="html">When He had come to the other side, to the country of the Gergesenes, there met Him two demon-possessed men, coming out of the tombs, exceedingly fierce, so that no one could pass that way. Matthew 8:28 NKJV</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/45976390/91338058-541b1280-e7a2-11ea-891f-daf48785f37d.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/45976390/91338058-541b1280-e7a2-11ea-891f-daf48785f37d.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Illness</title><link href="https://www.orchard.cc/posts/world/2020/07/08/illness" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Illness" /><published>2020-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.orchard.cc/posts/world/2020/07/08/illness</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.orchard.cc/posts/world/2020/07/08/illness">&lt;p&gt;We can only feel the tremor; we do not see the inner tension (of the tectonic
plates) that cause the tremor. This inner tension can build up over a long
period of time and release itself in the form of an earthquake. The earthquake
is just a by-product of this inner tension being released after a period of
time building, grinding, and finally breaking up underneath the surface of the
earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can only see the eruption; we do not see the inner turmoil boiling within
(the volcano) that cause the eruption. This inner turmoil can build up over a
long period of time before releasing itself in the form of a volcanic eruption.
The volcanic eruption is just a by-product of this turmoil being released after
a period of time building, seething, and finally erupting forth from within the
volcano.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is the same with people who erupt at others. It may be a by-product of that
which we do not see or know—the inner tensions of that person’s life grinding
beneath the surface of &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/culture/2019/09/25/retweets-do-not-imply-endorsement&quot;&gt;the facade&lt;/a&gt; that we do see and the inner turmoils of
that person’s life seething within them. After a period of time of being built
up within a person, you may see this person’s inner tensions and turmoils
released whilst around you in the form of angry outbursts, an eruption of words
spewing forth toward you, and other types of destructive behaviours that breaks
and shakes the calm and peaceful atmosphere that was present just moments ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this is not limited to the individual level; these tremors and
eruptions may also happen at the communal or societal level. In fact, you can
see such eruptions happening across America. For, as mentioned in the previous
message, Martin Luther King Jr. had “a dream that one day this nation will rise
up, live out the true meaning of its creed: ‘We hold these truths to be
self-evident, that all men are created equal’” so that his “four little children
will one day live in a nation where they will not be judged by the color of
their skin but by the content of their character.” However, as current events in
America can attest, Martin Luther King Jr.’s dream has not yet been realized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This racial tension has been building up in America (and elsewhere) for many
generations. This racial inequality has been grinding and causing friction
for many generations. For a long period of time, a certain people have been
seething with indignation at the racial injustices that they have faced and
experienced. So the eruptions (protests) that you see happening across America
(and elsewhere) is just a by-product of this inner tension and turmoil that is
being released after building up for a long period of time within society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a person unexpectedly erupts and spews words toward you, just realize that
is a symptom of an underlying cause, similarly to how fevers, coughs, fatigue,
loss of taste and smell, and the like, may be symptoms to an underlying illness
such as Covid-19. You may try to treat the symptoms but that does not resolve
the underlying illness that caused those symptoms in the first place. Similarly,
the protests happening around America (and elsewhere) are just a symptom of an
underlying social illness—racial inequality. You can try to treat the symptoms
by setting curfews or bringing in more law enforcement officers to quell the
unrest but that does not fix the underlying societal ills that cause those
symptoms in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without a remedy, contagious diseases like Covid-19 may continue to infect
people of this world. And without collective action, people who are ill with a
contagious virus like Covid-19 may spread the virus to others, thereby causing
the illness to spread within their community or society. It can be the same with
societal ills. Without a remedy, societal ills like racial inequality may
continue to infect people of this world. Without collective action, people who
are ill with a contagious disease—like hatred toward other races or beliefs
that you are superior to other races—may spread those diseased points of views
to others, thereby causing the illness to spread within their community or
society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the collective action of the people around the world—like shutting
down non-essential services, social distancing, refraining from going out unless
absolutely necessary, and wearing face masks when you do go out in public, and
the like—countries have been able to either eliminate the contagious disease
Covid-19 or flatten the curve. New Zealand was one of the countries that was
able to &lt;a href=&quot;https://time.com/5849910/new-zealand-eliminated-coronavirus/&quot; title=&quot;New Zealand Has Eliminated Coronavirus, Prime Minister Says&quot;&gt;halt the spread of Covid-19&lt;/a&gt;. This was done by making halting the
spread of Covid-19 a top priority. And this was made a top priority because
halting the spread of Covid-19 was identified as desirable for the greater good
of society. For, as mentioned in a &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/life/2019/12/25/taxes-and-abortion&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, we are called to live for
a higher purpose than just ourselves. We are called to live to be a
benefit/blessing to others in the community, city, province/state, and country
that they live in. New Zealanders decided to live for a higher purpose than
themselves. New Zealanders chose to live for the benefit of others in their
community, city, and country. Because of this collective and sustained effort
and vigilance by the citizens of New Zealand, they were able to halt the spread
of Covid-19. However, if people within a community or country stop working
together before the disease has been eliminated from said community or country,
then the disease may flare up again and continue to spread to others within the
community or country rather than be eliminated. And if people within a community
or country think that other things should take priority over halting the spread
of the disease, then the disease may flare up again and continue to spread to
other people within the community or country rather than be eliminated. This
scenario is happening in countries such as America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, it can take the collective action of the people within a community or
a country to eliminate societal diseases such as racial inequality. But it has
to be a top priority of that community or country. The people of that community
or country must also believe that it is for the greater good of society to
eliminate that societal disease. The people of that community or country
must be willing to do things for the collective benefit of others ahead of the
benefit of just themselves and their kind. However, if the people within a
community or country decide to put themselves ahead of the collective benefit of
others, then the spread of the societal disease shall continue unabated. As
well, if the people within a community or country stop working collectively
before the societal illness has been eliminated, then the societal illness may
flare up again and continue to spread to others. Like New Zealand’s response to
Covid-19, elimination of societal illnesses requires collective will, sustained
effort, and vigilance by the government and citizens of the community or
country. On the other hand, societal illnesses shall continue to spread within a
community or country if they follow a similar path to America’s response to
Covid-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a person experienced the symptoms associated with Covid-19, they would go
to the hospital to get tested and, if necessary, get treatment. Hospitals—and
the doctors and nurses and other essential workers who worked there—were at
the forefront of the community’s response to eliminating the disease. Doctors
and nurses and other essential workers were willing to work for the collective
benefit of others within their community; they put other people’s benefit ahead
of their own. At the very least, others ought to be willing to do the same.
However, as you can see in countries like America, some people are not willing
to do that. This selfishness—putting self ahead of others— can be a symptom
of an individual’s diseased soul. At the societal level, the selfishness of
putting one race above another can be symptom of a societal illness. Like
doctors and nurses and other essential workers, there must be workers who may
treat those who show symptoms of societal illness. Symptoms like hatred toward
other races or beliefs of superiority over other races. The workers who treat
the symptoms of societal illnesses may work in a kind of hospital—a hospital
for the soul, the church. For, as Jesus said to the scribes and Pharisees who
criticized Him eating and drinking with tax collectors and sinners: “Healthy
people don’t need a doctor; those who are sick do. I’ve come to call sinners to
change the way they think and act, not to call people who think they have God’s
approval” (Luke 5:31-32 GW). Yes, church and its workers ought to be at the
forefront of a community’s response to treating and eliminating societal
illnesses like how hospitals and its workers are at the forefront of a
community’s reponse to treating and eliminating diseases like Covid-19. For, if
the church and its workers are not willing to be at the forefront, then societal
illnesses may continue to spread unabated rather than be halted and eliminated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God bless.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="World" /><category term="Black Lives Matter" /><category term="Covid-19" /><category term="Inequality" /><category term="Societal Illness" /><summary type="html">We can only feel the tremor; we do not see the inner tension (of the tectonic plates) that cause the tremor. This inner tension can build up over a long period of time and release itself in the form of an earthquake. The earthquake is just a by-product of this inner tension being released after a period of time building, grinding, and finally breaking up underneath the surface of the earth.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/45976390/86523075-cde2ef80-be34-11ea-89cb-3158788ecbfa.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/45976390/86523075-cde2ef80-be34-11ea-89cb-3158788ecbfa.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Generational Promises</title><link href="https://www.orchard.cc/posts/world/2020/06/24/generational-promises" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Generational Promises" /><published>2020-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.orchard.cc/posts/world/2020/06/24/generational-promises</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.orchard.cc/posts/world/2020/06/24/generational-promises">&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;God said, “Take now your son, your only son [of promise], whom you love, Isaac,
and go to the region of Moriah, and offer him there as a burnt offering on one
of the mountains of which I shall tell you.”&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 22:2 AMP&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God instructed Abraham to take his son, Isaac, to the region of Moriah and offer
him there as a burnt offering on one of the mountains. Now, as mentioned in
previous posts, God can instruct you to go to a particular destination (as well
as take a particular route to said destination). In a &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/world/2020/05/14/without-hesitation&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;,
Peter was instructed by the Holy Spirit to go to Caesarea and speak with a man
named Cornelius. In &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/world/2020/04/30/vouch-for-him&quot;&gt;another post&lt;/a&gt;, Jesus had to go through Samaria to travel
to Galilee. And in yet &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/world/2020/04/15/fragmentary&quot;&gt;another post&lt;/a&gt;, a prophet named Samuel instructed Saul
to take a specific route back to his father’s home. Those posts suggested that
you follow the instructions of the Lord by faith and without hesitation. So
Abraham got up early in the morning, saddled his donkey, and took two of his
young men with him and his son Isaac; and he split the wood for the burnt
offering, and then he got up and went to the place of which God had told him.
And on the third day [of travel] Abraham looked up and saw the place in the
distance (Genesis 22:3-4 AMP).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abraham traveled for about three days to get to the place that God instructed
him to go. Likewise, the people from the stories in the previous posts—Peter,
Jesus, and Saul—traveled certain distances and lengths of time to get to the
place that the Holy Spirit instructed them to go. This time between when the
Holy Spirit instructs you to go somewhere to do something and when you get to
that somewhere provides a perfect opportunity for &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/life/2018/12/05/did-god-really-say&quot;&gt;the serpent&lt;/a&gt; to introduce
doubt in your heart. As mentioned in that post, the serpent can do that by
getting you to question whether or not God really said what we think He said. As
such, while Abraham (or we) travel to the place that the Lord instructed us to
go, Abraham (or we) may wonder whether it was God’s voice that we heard speaking
to us or if it was just our inner voice and imaginations. And if the serpent is
successful in introducing this doubt into our hearts, then we may abandon our
journey to the destination and instead turn around and go back. But that ought
not to be! Instead, like Abraham, we should not waver in our belief in what the
Lord had told us and continue marching forward until we reach the place that the
Lord instructed us to go. Therefore, as it was mentioned in that post, we must
realize when the serpent is trying to use this tactic against us so that we may
guard against falling for this tactic of his.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should also have the same mindset and thought process that Abraham had.
Abraham reasoned that if Isaac died, God was able to bring him back to life
again. And in a sense, Abraham did receive his son back from the dead (Hebrews
11:19 NLT). Abraham thought that nothing is impossible for God. And Abraham
reasoned that God is faithful—He keeps His promises because God is not a liar.
(One of God’s promises to Abraham required Isaac to grow up and marry someone
and start a family, which would be difficult to do if he were dead. Therefore,
Abraham reasoned that God would be able to bring his son back from the dead.)
Likewise, we should think that nothing is impossible for God. And we should
reason that God is faithful, that He shall keep His promises to us because He is
not a liar. Of course, as mentioned in &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/life/2018/12/12/parable-of-the-sower&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;, the serpent may try to
get you to doubt the veracity of what God told you. Whilst you are journeying
to where the Lord told you to go, the serpent may try to get you to doubt the
faithfulness of the Lord as well as His ability to keep His promises. And if the
serpent is successful in introducing this doubt into our hearts, we may abandon
our journey to the destination and instead turn around and go back. But that
ought not to be! Instead, like Abraham, we should not waver in our belief in
God’s faithfulness and abilities. Thus, as it was mentioned in that post, we
must realize when the serpent is trying to use this tactic against us so that we
may guard against falling for this tactic of his.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All these people died having faith. They didn’t receive the things that God
had promised them, but they saw these things coming in the distant future and
rejoiced. They acknowledged that they were living as strangers with no permanent
home on earth.&lt;cite&gt;Hebrews 11:13 GW&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God keeps His promises, but that does not mean that those promises of His shall
be fulfilled within your lifetime. Rather, some of the promises that God tells
you may be fulfilled within the lifetime of future generations. You may think of
these as generational promises. Some of the things that God promised to Abraham
did not happen within his lifetime; rather, they happened in future generations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An analogy can be found in the current events that are happening around the
world. A certain person had &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.archives.gov/files/press/exhibits/dream-speech.pdf&quot; title=&quot;I HAVE A DREAM...&quot;&gt;a dream&lt;/a&gt;: “A dream that one day this nation will
rise up, live out the true meaning of its creed: ‘We hold these truths to be
self-evident, that all men are created equal’” so that his “four little children
will one day live in a nation where they will not be judged by the color of
their skin but by the content of their character.” As current events can attest,
Martin Luther King Jr.’s dream was not fulfilled within his lifetime, but that
does that mean that his dream shall never be fulfilled. Rather, that dream of
his may be fulfilled within the lifetime of future generations, maybe even
within the lifetime of this generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, you should not lose hope or faith in God just because you do not see
His promises or your dreams come to pass within your lifetime. Rather, similarly
to Abraham, you should rejoice because of your belief that His promises and your
dreams shall come to pass in future generations. And similarly to Abraham, you
should share with your children the promises that God has made to you so that
they and future generations may also rejoice and know what is to come in their
lifetimes or the lifetimes of their descendents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God bless.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="World" /><category term="Dreams" /><category term="Future" /><category term="Generational" /><category term="Promises" /><summary type="html">God said, “Take now your son, your only son [of promise], whom you love, Isaac, and go to the region of Moriah, and offer him there as a burnt offering on one of the mountains of which I shall tell you.”Genesis 22:2 AMP</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/45976390/85609800-6f439780-b624-11ea-8896-32d43c439eb4.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/45976390/85609800-6f439780-b624-11ea-8896-32d43c439eb4.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Without Hesitation</title><link href="https://www.orchard.cc/posts/world/2020/05/14/without-hesitation" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Without Hesitation" /><published>2020-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.orchard.cc/posts/world/2020/05/14/without-hesitation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.orchard.cc/posts/world/2020/05/14/without-hesitation">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A man named Cornelius lived in the city of Caesarea. He was a Roman army
officer in the Italian Regiment. One day, about three in the afternoon, he had a
vision. He clearly saw an angel from God come to him and say, “Cornelius! Send
messengers now to the city of Joppa, and summon a man whose name is Simon Peter.
He is a guest of Simon, a leatherworker, whose house is by the sea.”
&lt;cite&gt;Acts 10:1,3,5,6 GW&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a man named Cornelius. God dispatched an angel to tell him to send
people to the city of Joppa to summon a man named Simon Peter. The angel of God
gave Cornelius specific instructions to follow. As mentioned in a
&lt;a href=&quot;/posts/world/2020/04/15/fragmentary&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, the Lord can give you specific instructions to follow. He
may give you these instructions directly as you pray to Him. Or, He may give you
these directions through men and women of God (such as prophets), as was the
case in that previous post. Or, as is the case in this story, He may send angels
to deliver His instructions. And as suggested in that previous post, you should
follow the instructions that the Lord gives you (whether it be directly through
your prayer time with Him or indirectly through prophets) lest you miss the
connections that the Lord has planned for you. Cornelius decided to listen to
and follow the instructions that the angel of God gave to him. For, when the
angel who spoke to him had departed, Cornelius called two of his household
servants and a devout soldier from among those who waited on him continually. So
when he had explained all these things to them, he sent them to Joppa (Acts
10:7-8 NKJV).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you follow the instructions of the Lord, He shall make sure that what He
says comes true since the Lord does not lie; He is a faithful God. When you do
your part by obediently following and acting upon His word, the Lord will do
His part to honor your faith so that His word comes to pass and bears fruit.
That is what happened when Cornelius decided to follow the instructions that
the angel of God gave to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Around noon the next day, while Cornelius’ men were on their way and coming
close to Joppa, Peter went on the roof to pray. He became hungry and wanted to
eat. While the food was being prepared, he fell into a trance. He saw the sky
open and something like a large linen sheet being lowered by its four corners to
the ground. This happened three times. Then the sheet was quickly taken into the
sky.&lt;cite&gt;Acts 10:9,10,11,16 GW&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around noon, while the messengers that Cornelius sent were nearing Joppa, Simon
Peter went to pray on the roof of the house that he was lodging at. Whilst
praying, he became hungry and wanted to eat; but the food that was being
prepared was not ready. Whilst the food was being prepared, he fell into a
trance. Now, this is reminiscent of the story of Jesus’ encounter with the woman
at the well that was mentioned in the &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/world/2020/04/30/vouch-for-him&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;. As mentioned in that
story, Jesus arrived at a Samaritan town called Sychar, near the tract of land
that Jacob gave to his son Joseph; and Jacob’s well was there. So Jesus, tired
as He was from His journey, sat down by the well. It was then about the sixth
hour (noon) (John 4:5-6 AMP). Jesus arrived at a Samaritan town called Sychar
and sat down by Jacob’s well at around noon, after a long walk from Judea. This
is the same time that Simon Peter went on the roof to pray. Jesus was alone at
the time because his disciples had gone into the village to buy some food (John
4:8 NLT). Jesus was waiting alone at the well whilst food was being bought for
Him by His disciples. Simon Peter was praying alone whilst food was being
prepared for him by his host. Whilst waiting alone at the well, a Samaritan
woman came to draw water, and Jesus said to her, “Please give me a drink” (John
4:7 NLT). While Peter was still thinking about the vision, the Spirit said to
him, “Simon, three men are looking for you. So get up and go downstairs. Do not
hesitate to go with them, for I have sent them” (Acts 10:19-20 NIV). The Lord
spoke with Simon Peter and told him to go with the men who were seeking him so
that Cornelius’ decision to faithfully follow and obey the instructions that the
Lord gave to him would bear fruit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus was tired and weary from His journey, so He could have ignored the woman
who came to the well to draw water. He could have sat there and just waited for
His disciples to come back with food. But He did not. Instead, He chose to speak
with that woman. Likewise, Simon Peter was hungry, so he could have ignored the
messengers who came to see him. He could have just sat there on the roof of the
house that he was lodging at and waited for the food that was being prepared to
be ready. But he did not. Instead, Peter went down and said to the men, “I’m the
one you’re looking for. Why have you come?” (Acts 10:21 NIV).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, many times the Lord may tell you to do something when you prefer to be
doing something else. Like Jesus, the Holy Spirit may tell you to speak to
someone when you prefer to rest because you are tired and weary. The Holy Spirit
told Jesus to speak to the woman who walked toward Him at the well. Likewise,
the Holy Spirit may tell you to talk to someone that walks or stands or sits by
you when you prefer to just sit or stand on the subway or bus with your
earphones on listening to music whilst on the way to school or work. Or, like
Simon Peter, the Holy Spirit may tell you to go and speak with someone when you
prefer to eat because you are hungry. Yes, the Holy Spirit may tell you to speak
to someone whilst waiting in line to order lunch or sitting at your table while
the meal that you ordered at a restaurant is being prepared. Or, the Holy Spirit
may tell you to go and spend some time with a person or group of people when you
prefer to spend some time with your family, friends, or partner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When such a scenario happens, you have a choice to make: do what the Lord wants
you to do, or do what you want to do. I suggest that you do what the Lord wants
to do. For, when you do your part by obediently following and acting upon His
word, the Lord will do His part to honor your faith such that His word comes to
pass and bears fruit. You may not fully understand why the Lord wants you to do
or say something to someone. That is okay. You don’t have to understand why He
wants you to do or say that something. You just have to trust in Him. For, as
the Holy Spirit said to Simon Peter: do not hesitate. Do not hesitate to do what
the Lord tells you to do. Do not doubt or question why the Lord is telling you
to do or say something. All you have to do is do what the Lord tells you to do,
without hesitation or doubt, but by faith. And when you do that, you shall see
your obedient actions to His words bear fruit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus decided to do what the the Lord wanted Him to do; and as mentioned in the
previous post, the woman He encountered at the well, and many other people in
Samaria, came to believe in Him after hearing the woman and Him speak to them.
Likewise, Simon Peter chose to do what the Lord wanted Him to do. Simon Peter
decided to go with the messengers back to Cornelius’ home. On the following day
he [and the others] entered Caesarea. Cornelius was waiting for them, and had
called together his relatives and close friends (Acts 10:24 AMP).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cornelius vouched for Simon Peter—the man of God that an angel instructed him
to summon—to his relatives and close friends. Because Cornelius vouched for
Simon Peter, Cornelius’ relatives and close friends also came to hear what this
man of God had to say. Now, this is similar to what the woman at the well from
the previous post did. The woman vouched for Jesus and told the people of her
village to come and see and hear what He had to say. And as mentioned in another
post, it is also similar to what Saul’s servant did. Saul’s servant vouched for
a man of God—Samuel the Prophet—suggesting that they go and see him and hear
what he has to say. And as mentioned in the previous post, you ought to vouch
for the men and women of God whom you view as credible to other people so that
they go and see them and hear what they have to say. Cornelius vouched to his
relatives and close friends. You can do likewise with your relatives and close
friends. Saul’s servant vouched to his boss. You can do likewise with your
bosses, managers, and colleagues. The woman at the well vouched to acquaintances
and strangers whom she did not know. You can do likewise with people whom you do
not know (well).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Samaritan woman said to him, “You are a Jew and I am a Samaritan woman.
How can you ask me for a drink?” (For Jews do not associate with Samaritans.)
&lt;cite&gt;John 4:9 NIV&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Peter told them, “You know it is against our laws for a Jewish man to enter a
Gentile home like this or to associate with you. But God has shown me that I
should no longer think of anyone as impure or unclean. So I came without
objection as soon as I was sent for. Now tell me why you sent for me.”
&lt;cite&gt;Acts 10:28-29 NLT&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, Jews did not associate with Samaritans. Nevertheless, Jesus, a Jew,
spoke with a Samaritan woman; and subsequently spoke to other Samaritans in the
town of Sychar. At the time, it was against the law for Jews to associate with
or visit Gentiles. Nevertheless, Simon Peter came without hesitation to
Cornelius’ home and spoke with the people gathered there. Likewise, you may
think that you ought to shun rather than associate with a person or group of
people for some particular reason. Now, some of those reasons were mentioned in
previous posts. For example, a &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/culture/2019/10/25/tax-collectors-and-sinners&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; mentioned that you may think
that you should shun rather than associate with those whom you view as wicked.
&lt;a href=&quot;/posts/culture/2019/09/25/retweets-do-not-imply-endorsement&quot;&gt;Another post&lt;/a&gt; suggested that you may think that you should shun rather than
associate with those who do or say things that you do not endorse or agree with.
For example, you may think that you should shun rather than associate with those
who have different political views or sexual preferences or religious beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that should not be! Instead, you should follow the example that Jesus and
Simon Peter set. Like Jesus, you should be willing to associate with those whom
others do not associate with. At that time, Jews and Samaritans had differing
religious beliefs. For, as the woman at the well said to Jesus, “Our ancestors
worshiped on this mountain, but you Jews claim that the place where we must
worship is in Jerusalem” (John 4:20 NIV). Likewise, He may not have agreed with
the fact that the woman was living with a man who was not her husband. And yet,
that did not stop Him from speaking with her instead of shunning her for her
choices. And like Simon Peter, you should not be hesitant to go and associate
with those whom others do not associate with. You should not raise any objection
when the Lord tells you to associate with people whom others would shun. Rather,
you should go by faith. And when you do that, you shall see your obedient action
to His instructions bear fruit. That is what happened with Simon Peter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simon Peter decided to go with the messengers back to Cornelius’ home; and he
spoke to those who were gathered at Cornelius’ home. And while Peter was still
speaking these words, the Holy Spirit fell on all those who were listening to
the message [confirming God’s acceptance of Gentiles] (Acts 10:44 AMP). And the
Jewish believers who came with Peter were amazed that the gift of the Holy
Spirit had been poured out on the Gentiles, too (Acts 10:45 NLT). Simon Peter
was willing to go and associate with them—Gentiles—because God showed him
that he should no longer think of anyone as impure or unclean. Likewise, you too
should no longer think of anyone as impure or unclean just because you do not
agree or endorse their actions, lifestyle, or views. Rather, like Simon Peter,
you too ought to be willing to go and associate with them. And when you do that,
you too may see the Holy Spirit poured out on them. But this does not happen if
you refuse to associate with others because you judge them to be impure or
unclean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(It is of course possible that you do not care about others, such as those whom
you disagree with or view as wicked. Well, as mentioned in a &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/culture/2019/11/06/a-tale-of-two-cities&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;,
whilst you may not care about others and their eternal destiny, the Lord cares
about all—including those whom people view as wicked. As such, you should put
aside your personal misgivings and go without doubt and hesitation to those whom
you would not normally associate with.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it was mentioned in the previous post, Jesus said to the woman at the well:
“If you knew the gift of God, and who it is who says to you, ‘Give Me a drink,’
you would have asked Him, and He would have given you living water” (John 4:10
NASB). For, “whoever drinks the water I give them will never thirst. Indeed, the
water I give them will become in them a spring of water welling up to eternal
life” (John 4:14 NIV). This living water—the Holy Spirit—is not only
available to Jews; it is available to all. Jesus said this to a Samaritan woman.
Thus, if she asked Jesus for this living water, then she would receive it! And
this living water was available to the Gentiles who gathered at Cornelius’ home.
And it is also available to those whom you would shun rather than associate with
because you judge them to be wicked or impure. Therefore, go to those whom the
Lord tells you to go to and speak to. Even if they are people whom you would not
normally associate with for whatever reason. And when you do that, you will see
your obedient actions done by faith bear fruit. You will see the Spirit of God
pour out on those whom you did not expect would be poured out to. You will see
people whom you would least expect receive the Holy Spirit similarly to how
people did not expect to see Saul prophesying after the Holy Spirit was poured
out onto him and similarly to how the Jews were amazed because they did not
expect the Holy Spirit to be poured out onto the Gentiles. So just believe. And
go, without hesitations or doubts, but by faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God bless.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="World" /><category term="Spirit" /><category term="Unhesitant Faith" /><category term="Vouch" /><summary type="html">A man named Cornelius lived in the city of Caesarea. He was a Roman army officer in the Italian Regiment. One day, about three in the afternoon, he had a vision. He clearly saw an angel from God come to him and say, “Cornelius! Send messengers now to the city of Joppa, and summon a man whose name is Simon Peter. He is a guest of Simon, a leatherworker, whose house is by the sea.” Acts 10:1,3,5,6 GW</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/45976390/81978253-3f52ae80-95f9-11ea-92ab-8506622ca7c5.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/45976390/81978253-3f52ae80-95f9-11ea-92ab-8506622ca7c5.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Vouch For Him</title><link href="https://www.orchard.cc/posts/world/2020/04/30/vouch-for-him" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vouch For Him" /><published>2020-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-04-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.orchard.cc/posts/world/2020/04/30/vouch-for-him</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.orchard.cc/posts/world/2020/04/30/vouch-for-him">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The woman left her water jar beside the well and ran back to the village,
telling everyone, “Come and see a man who told me everything I ever did! Could
he possibly be the Messiah?” &lt;cite&gt;John 4:28-29 NLT&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The servant said to him, “Look here, in this city there is a man of God, and the
man is held in honor; everything that he says comes true. Now let us go there;
perhaps he can advise us about our journey [and tell us where we should go].”
&lt;cite&gt;1 Samuel 9:6 AMP&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The woman told everyone in her village to come see a man who told her everything
she ever did. For, while speaking with the man, she mentioned that she doesn’t
have a husband. To which, Jesus said to her, “You have correctly said, ‘I do not
have a husband’; for you have had five husbands, and the man you are now living
with is not your husband. You have said this truthfully.” So the woman said to
Him, “Sir, I see that You are a prophet” (John 4:17-19 AMP). They had just met
but Jesus knew these details about her. Astounded by the conversation that they
had, the woman left her water jar beside the well, ran back to the village, and
told everyone to come see a man—Jesus—whom they did not personally know.
Now, if you recall, this isn’t that different from the story of Saul’s search
for his father’s missing donkeys that was mentioned in the previous message. In
the previous post, Saul’s servant told him to go see a man of God—Samuel the
Prophet—whom he did not personally know. Then Saul said to his servant, “Your
suggestion is a good one. Come, let us go.” And they went to the town where the
man of God was (1 Samuel 9:10 LEB). Whilst conversing, Samuel the Prophet told
Saul: As for the donkeys you lost three days ago, do not worry about them; they
have been found (1 Samuel 9:20 NIV). They had just met but Samuel the Prophet
knew those details about his life. Saul had not met Samuel the Prophet before.
We know this because Saul approached Samuel inside the gateway and said, “Please
tell me where the seer’s house is” (1 Samuel 9:18 GW). Saul did not know that he
was speaking to the seer—Samuel the Prophet—whom he was looking for because
they had never met before! Now, Saul agreed to go and see this man of God
because his servant had vouched for him. The servant told Saul the man of God is
highly respected by all; and he is credible because everything he says &lt;em&gt;comes&lt;/em&gt;
true. This is not too different from what the woman told people in her village.
The woman vouched for the man of God whom she just met at the well. The woman
told the people of her village that everything Jesus said to me &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; true. Even
though the woman just met Jesus at the well, she testified that He told her all
that she ever did. So the people came streaming from the village to see him
(John 4:30 NLT).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, you might know men and women of God—such as prophets—whom you view as
being highly respected and credible. You may view the man or woman of God as
honorable and credible because that is the reputation that they have built. Or
you may hold those views of the man or woman of God because of your (or someone
you trust’s) personal experiences and encounters with them; and during your
personal encounters with the man or woman of God, they told you things from your
past and/or told you things that came to pass in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, like Saul’s servant and the woman at the well, you should vouch for the
men and women of God whom you know and see as credible. Others might not know
these men and women of God. But you do, through your personal experiences and
encounters with them. As such, you may testify to the credibility of these men
and women of God and share your personal experiences with them to those who do
not know them. If you do not vouch for these men and women of God, then others
may not go to see them. And if they do not go to see them, they may not get the
opportunity to experience what you experienced when you encountered the man or
woman of God. And what you experienced may have been profound and life-changing.
Thus, like Saul’s servant and the woman at the well, you should vouch for the
men and women of God whom you view as credible and recommend others to go and
see them so that they too may have profound and life-changing experiences and
encounters with them; and be blessed by them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is what happened to Saul, as mentioned in the previous post. But that does
not happen if Saul’s servant does not vouch for the man of God and suggest that
he go and see him. Likewise, the people of the village would not have profound
experience if the woman at the well did not vouch for Jesus and recommend that
they go and see him. And that is what happened. Many of the Samaritans from that
town believed in him because of the woman’s testimony, “He told me everything I
ever did.” So when the Samaritans came to him, they urged him to stay with them,
and he stayed two days. And because of his words many more became believers.
They said to the woman, “We no longer believe just because of what you said; now
we have heard for ourselves, and we know that this man really is the Savior of
the world” (John 4:39-42 NIV). Many believed because of the woman’s testimony.
And many more believed after hearing directly from Him. Yes, as seen in these
stories, there are multitude of ways for a person to come to believe in Him. A
person may come to believe in Jesus after hearing your testimony. A person may
also come to believe in Him through men and women of God whom you recommend that
they go see. A person may come to believe in Jesus after hearing directly from
Him. Or, as Jesus said to someone: “Unless you people see signs and wonders, you
will by no means believe” (John 4:48 NKJV). Yes, not everyone in the village
believed in Jesus after hearing the woman’s testimony; they only believed in Him
after they themselves heard Him directly. Likewise, not everyone shall believe
in Jesus after hearing your testimony. Instead, they may need to hear directly
from Jesus or from men and women of God before believing in Him. And some people
will only believe in Jesus after seeing signs and wonders. (Of course, Jesus
desires everyone to believe in Him and be saved, so you should use every tool in
your toolbox to reach each person. Thus, if your testimony will convince them
to believe in Him, then you should share your testimony with them. Or, if asking
a person to go and hear from a man or woman of God will convince a person to
believe in Jesus, then you should do that. If signs and wonders will convince a
person to believe in Jesus, then you should do that. And the like.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in the previous post, Samuel the Prophet told Saul all of the signs
that he would see if he took a particular route back to his father’s house. He
told Saul that he would meet two people by Rachel’s tomb at Zelzah who will tell
you that the donkey’s that you have been looking for have been found. He then
told Saul that he would meet three men by the big oak tree in Tabor who would
greet him and give him two loaves of bread. And then he told Saul that he would
meet a group of prophets and worshippers at Gibeah, where the Spirit of the Lord
would come upon him; and he shall prophesy with them and be changed into a new
person. Then it happened. As Saul turned and started to leave, God gave him a
new heart, and all Samuel’s &lt;em&gt;signs&lt;/em&gt; were fulfilled that day (1 Samuel 10:9 NLT).
Yes, Saul went to see and hear from a man of God; and he witnessed signs come to
pass, which had a profound effect on his life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, men and women of God shall witness signs and wonders come to pass when
they follow the Lord’s direction. Before Jesus came to Samaria, He was in Judea.
He left Judea and departed again to Galilee. But He needed to go through Samaria
(John 4:3-4 NKJV). Now, to be clear: Jesus did not &lt;em&gt;have to&lt;/em&gt; go through Samaria
to go back to Galilee. At the time, there were more than one route from Judea to
Galilee. He could have taken a different route back to Galilee from Judea. But
it says He &lt;em&gt;needed to&lt;/em&gt; go through Samaria because the Holy Spirit instructed Him
to take a specific route—Judea to Galilee via Samaria—for a reason: so the
people of that city would come to believe in Him and be saved. The Lord knew the
people of that city were ready and receptive to hearing the Good News of Jesus
Christ. So the Lord sent Jesus there to share the Gospel with them. And as it
was mentioned earlier, many of the Samaritans of that city decided to believe in
Him because of the testimony of the woman and the word that He shared with them.
However, this does not happen if Jesus takes a different route back to Galilee
from Judea. This only happened because Jesus chose to follow the instructions of
the Lord by going through Samaria whilst on the way back to Galilee from Judea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Do you think the work of harvesting will not begin until the summer ends four
months from now? Look around you! Vast fields of human souls are ripening all
around us, and are ready now for reaping. &lt;cite&gt;John 4:35 TLB&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Men and women of God: Look all around you. The field of human souls is ready for
reaping. You do not have to wait for some future time or season or event before
reaping. The field is ready now. Some are waiting expectantly for a so-called
Third Pentecost where they envision a great outpouring of His Spirit and reaping
of souls. You do not have to wait for such a time. No! The field is ready now.
You can witness His Spirit being poured out on people now. What did Jesus say to
the woman at the well (besides the number of husbands that she’s had)? Jesus
said to her, “If you knew the gift of God, and who it is who says to you, ‘Give
Me a drink,’ you would have asked Him, and He would have given you living
water” (John 4:10 NASB). For, “whoever drinks the water I give them will never
thirst. Indeed, the water I give them will become in them a spring of water
welling up to eternal life” (John 4:14 NIV). He is talking about the Spirit of
God. That is the living water that He mentions. And as He said to her, all you
have to do is ask Him (by faith) and He will give you living water—the Spirit
of God. Now, He also spoke of this living water to others. To others, He said:
Whoever believes in me, as Scripture has said, rivers of living water will flow
from within them. By this he meant the Spirit, whom those who believed in him
were later to receive.” (John 7:38-39 NIV). The Spirit of God shall come upon
whoever believes in Him. So you do not have to wait until some future time or
season or event before seeing the Spirit of God come upon people. Instead, you
need to go out into the field and reap. For the field is ready for reaping. And
you do that by testifying to others, similarly to what the woman at the well
did; you do that by bringing people to Jesus; and you do that by suggesting
people go see men and women of God, similarly to what Saul’s servant did. And
the like. When you do that, you shall witness people believe in Him; and
consequently, you shall witness the Spirit of God come upon them. Just believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God bless.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="World" /><category term="Prophecy" /><category term="Reap" /><category term="Spirit" /><category term="Souls" /><category term="Vouch" /><summary type="html">The woman left her water jar beside the well and ran back to the village, telling everyone, “Come and see a man who told me everything I ever did! Could he possibly be the Messiah?” John 4:28-29 NLT The servant said to him, “Look here, in this city there is a man of God, and the man is held in honor; everything that he says comes true. Now let us go there; perhaps he can advise us about our journey [and tell us where we should go].” 1 Samuel 9:6 AMP</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/45976390/80776824-42e23200-8b31-11ea-86fe-8de7609348c7.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/45976390/80776824-42e23200-8b31-11ea-86fe-8de7609348c7.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Fragmentary</title><link href="https://www.orchard.cc/posts/world/2020/04/15/fragmentary" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fragmentary" /><published>2020-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.orchard.cc/posts/world/2020/04/15/fragmentary</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.orchard.cc/posts/world/2020/04/15/fragmentary">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Love never fails [it never fades nor ends]. But as for prophecies, they will
pass away; as for tongues, they will cease; as for the gift of special
knowledge, it will pass away. For we know in part, and we prophesy in part [for
our knowledge is fragmentary and incomplete].
&lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 13:8-9 AMP&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Love never comes to an end. There is the gift of speaking what God has revealed,
but it will no longer be used. There is the gift of speaking in other languages,
but it will stop by itself. There is the gift of knowledge, but it will no
longer be used. Our knowledge is incomplete and our ability to speak what God
has revealed is incomplete. &lt;cite&gt;1 Corinthians 13:8-9 GW&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in the previous post, the Lord knows better than you and your
circle of family, friends, confidantes, et al. about you and the direction that
you should go in your life. And that is because the guidance and advice that
other people give to you is limited by their knowledge. For, as it is written in
the Scripture quoted above, our knowledge is fragmentary and incomplete. We only
know in part, so we can only prophesy in part. This is because we can only speak
of what we know. And what we know is incomplete and partial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why the messages that are shared here may seem incomplete. It is because
the Lord has only revealed a fragment of the whole picture. A piece of the whole
puzzle. And this portion of the whole puzzle is all that I can share since that
is all that the Lord has shared to me. It is also why subsequent posts may build
upon previous messages. It is because the Lord reveals a new fragment/piece of
the puzzle that connects with what He has previously revealed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;After this I will pour out My Spirit on all humanity; then your sons and your
daughters will prophesy, your old men will have dreams, and your young men will
see visions. &lt;cite&gt;Joel 2:28 HCSB&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This gift of prophecy is not limited to a select few. In fact, as it is written
in the Scripture that is quoted above, there shall be a time when the Lord pours
out His Spirit on all people; your sons and daughters will prophesy, your old
men will dream dreams, and your young men will see visions. A preview of this
time may be seen in the story of Saul. (Yes, the same Saul whom a prophet named
Samuel anointed to be king over the people of Israel because they demanded that
a king—instead of the Lord—lead them and &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/world/2019/01/16/drain-the-swamp&quot;&gt;fight their battles&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;/posts/life/2019/01/23/the-battle-is-the-lords&quot;&gt;save them from their troubles&lt;/a&gt;.) After Samuel the Prophet anointed Saul as
king over the people of Israel, Samuel the Prophet told Saul: When you leave me
today, you’ll meet two men near Rachel’s tomb at Zelzah in the territory of
Benjamin. They’ll tell you, “The donkeys you’ve been looking for have been found
(1 Samuel 10:2 CEV). Go on from there until you reach the big oak tree at Tabor,
where you’ll meet three men on their way to worship God at Bethel (1 Samuel 10:3
CEV). After they greet you, they’ll give you two loaves of bread (1 Samuel 10:4
CEV). Next, go to Gibeah, where the Philistines have an army camp. As you’re
going into the town, you’ll meet a group of prophets coming down from the place
of worship. They’ll be going along prophesying while others are walking in front
of them, playing small harps, small drums, and flutes (1 Samuel 10:5 CEV). At
that time the Spirit of the Lord will come powerfully upon you, and you will
prophesy with them. You will be changed into a different person (1 Samuel 10:5
NLT).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samuel the Prophet gave Saul specific directions as to which route/path to
follow to travel back to his father’s home. Samuel the Prophet told Saul to go
to Rachel’s tomb at Zelzah, where he will meet two men. Then Samuel the Prophet
told Saul to go to the big tree at Tabor, where he will meet three men who will
greet him and give him two loaves of bread. And finally, Samuel the Prophet told
Saul to go to Gibeah, where he will meet a group of prophets and worshippers. As
is mentioned in the previous post, Lord knows best which direction/route you
should take to get to your destination because He is all-knowing. He knows what
will happen when you take a certain route. And He knows whether or not you will
cross paths with obstacles and/or dead ends along the route. He knows whom and
what you will encounter along the way. And He knows exactly where you shall come
across these obstacles and people along your journey. Because He is all-seeing.
That is why Samuel the Prophet was able to give Saul such detailed information
regarding whom he would encounter (and where) along the way back to his father’s
home. It is because the Lord revealed those specific details to Samuel so that
he would relay that information to Saul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in the previous post, whether or not you follow the directions that
the Lord advise you to go is ultimately up to you. You may choose to follow the
Lord’s directions. Or you may choose to follow different directions. Maybe your
own directions or the directions that your family, friends, and confidantes, et
al. advise you to go. Saul too could have chosen to not follow the directions
that the Lord gave him through Samuel the Prophet. Rather, Saul could have taken
a different route. Instead, Saul could have gone back to his father’s home via
the way he came. Saul originally left his father’s home because the donkeys of
Kish, Saul’s father, had wandered off and were lost. So Kish said to his son
Saul, “Please take one of the servants with you and arise, go look for the
donkeys” (1 Samuel 9:3 AMP). So they set off to look for the donkeys. He passed
through the hill country of Ephraim and passed through the land of Shalishah,
but they did not find them. Then they passed through the land of Shaalim, but
they were not there. Then he passed through the land of the Benjamites, but they
did not find them (1 Samuel 9:4 NASB). And finally, they entered the region of
Zuph, and Saul said to his servant, “Let’s go home. By now my father will be
more worried about us than about the donkeys!” (1 Samuel 9:5 NLT). From his
father’s home, Saul went through the hill country of Ephraim, then through the
land of Shalishah, then through the land of Shaalim, then through the land of
the Benjamites, and finally to the region of Zuph. That is the route that he
took. Saul could have gone back the way that he came. He could have went from
the region of Zuph, then through the land of the Benjamites, then through the
land of Shaalim, then through the land of Shalishah, and then through the hill
country of Ephraim to reach his father’s home. But he did not. Instead, Saul
chose to follow the directions/route that the Lord told him to go through Samuel
the Prophet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, Saul met with Samuel the Prophet whilst in the region of Zuph. For, after
Saul suggested to his servant that they go back home, the servant said to him,
“Look here, in this city there is a man of God, and the man is held in honor;
everything that he says comes true. Now let us go there; perhaps he can advise
us about our journey [and tell us where we should go]” (1 Samuel 9:6 AMP). Now,
in this case, the servant made a suggestion to Saul; and he followed the advice
of his servant. They went and met the man of God—Samuel. For, as mentioned in
the previous post, you do not have to stop listening or seeking or following the
advice of others such as your family, friends, and confidantes (or in this case,
a servant). But you may have to choose whose advice you shall follow if the
Lord’s advice is different from other people’s advice. When they met the man of
God, Samuel gave them detailed directions of the path to take. And Saul chose to
follow Samuel’s directions. This is because Saul trusted the advice that Samuel
the prophet gave to him. Saul did not personally know Samuel the Prophet. And as
it was mentioned in the previous post, you might not give your trust to others
if you do not know them. Yet, Saul trusted Samuel the Prophet’s advice. Why is
that? I reckon it is because of Samuel the Prophet’s reputation. Samuel the
Prophet is highly respected by all since everything he says comes to pass. You
may not know someone personally, but you may hear good things about that person
through others (such as those whom you do trust). And those people may vouch for
the someone whom you do not know. And because of this, you may choose to trust
that person even though you do not personally know them. That is what Saul did.
Even though Saul did not personally know Samuel the Prophet, he chose to trust
and follow the guidance that Samuel the Prophet gave to him because his servant
had told him that Samuel the Prophet is trustworthy and reputable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Saul turned and started to leave, God gave him a new heart, and all Samuel’s
signs were fulfilled that day. When Saul and his servant arrived at Gibeah, they
saw a group of prophets coming toward them. Then the Spirit of God came
powerfully upon Saul, and he, too, began to prophesy (1 Samuel 10:9-10 NLT). All
the signs that Samuel detailed were fulfilled that day. But that does not happen
if Saul chooses to not follow the directions that the Lord gave to him through
Samuel the Prophet. If Saul chose to take a different route home, then he would
not have crossed paths with the two men that were by Rachel’s tomb at Zeltzah;
and the two men would not have had an opportunity to tell Saul that the donkey’s
that they were looking for have been found. If Saul chose to take a different
route home, then he would not have encountered the three men by the big oak tree
in Tabor; and those three men would not have had an opportunity to greet him or
give him two loaves of bread. And if Saul chose to take a different route home,
then he would not have come across a group of prophets and worshippers; and the
Spirit of God would not have come upon him, resulting in him prophesying with
them. So, you should follow the guidance that the Lord gives you (whether it be
directly as you pray to the Lord and commune with Him or indirectly through
prophets and other people) lest you miss the connections that the Lord has
prepared for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Spirit of the Lord came upon Saul; and he started prophesying. That is a
preview of the time that is to come when the Lord pours out His Spirit on all
humanity like He did with Saul. And like Saul, your sons and your daughters will
start to prophesy, your old men will dream dreams, your young men will see
visions. When all who knew him formerly saw that he prophesied with prophets,
the people said to one another, “What is this that has happened to the son of
Kish? Is Saul also among the prophets?” (1 Samuel 10:11 LEB). People who knew
Saul saw him prophesying with prophets. They were surprised by this. They did
not expect to see Saul prophesying with prophets. They did not realize that the
Spirit of the Lord came upon him and changed him into a different person. Thus,
the people who knew him wondered what happened to cause him to start prophesying
with prophets. Like the people who used to know Saul, the people who knew you
will also wonder what happened to you when the Spirit of the Lord comes upon you
and they see you prophesying. The people who knew you will be surprised to see
you prophesying because they do not expect it. They may have been surprised at
the unexpected sight of you prophesying because they know your past. Your past
actions. Your past misdeeds. Your flaws and imperfections. The skeletons in your
closet that they think preclude you from being loved and accepted by God. But
what they may not know is that God’s love never fails; it neither fades nor
ends. As such, irregardless of your past, the Lord is willing to pour out His
Spirit upon you. And just like Saul, you shall be changed into a different
person. Just believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God bless.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="World" /><category term="Knowledge" /><category term="Prophecy" /><category term="Spirit" /><category term="Trust" /><summary type="html">Love never fails [it never fades nor ends]. But as for prophecies, they will pass away; as for tongues, they will cease; as for the gift of special knowledge, it will pass away. For we know in part, and we prophesy in part [for our knowledge is fragmentary and incomplete]. 1 Corinthians 13:8-9 AMP Love never comes to an end. There is the gift of speaking what God has revealed, but it will no longer be used. There is the gift of speaking in other languages, but it will stop by itself. There is the gift of knowledge, but it will no longer be used. Our knowledge is incomplete and our ability to speak what God has revealed is incomplete. 1 Corinthians 13:8-9 GW</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/45976390/79184573-85daa080-7de2-11ea-9c28-add63ae2e411.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/45976390/79184573-85daa080-7de2-11ea-9c28-add63ae2e411.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Circle Of Trust</title><link href="https://www.orchard.cc/posts/life/2020/03/27/circle-of-trust" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Circle Of Trust" /><published>2020-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.orchard.cc/posts/life/2020/03/27/circle-of-trust</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.orchard.cc/posts/life/2020/03/27/circle-of-trust">&lt;p&gt;In the previous message, it was suggested that you should let the Lord be your
Shepherd. For, when you do that, you shall not lack anything in any sphere of
your life since the Lord shall give you more than enough for your needs in all
aspects of your life. But it can be hard to let someone be your guide in life if
you do not trust that person. Likewise, if you do not trust a person—whether
it be the Lord or someone else—it can be hard to listen to their advice let
alone follow their guidance. For, if you don’t trust a person, you may not
believe that they have your best interests at heart nor may you think that they
know which direction to go would be best for your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can be a multitude of reasons why you do not trust a person. Maybe you
used to trust a person but then lost trust in that person. This can happen to
children as they grow up. I reckon that a baby is not born with distrust in
their parents. Babies trust and rely on their parents to love them, take care of
them, feed them, wipe them, comfort them, keep them safe, and the like. In other
words, babies trust and rely on their parents to be their shepherd. Babies trust
and rely on their parents to provide them with more than enough for all their
needs so that they don’t lack in any aspect of their life. But as the baby grows
up into a toddler and beyond, sometimes things happen that may cause that person
to stop trusting in their parents. The same thing could happen to those who
(used to) believe in or trust in the Lord. Maybe something happened such that
you no longer believe in or trust in the Lord to be your Shepherd and provider
in all aspects of your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, it is also possible that you never trusted a person. It could
be because you do not know the person; they are a stranger to you. As such, you
do not know them to give them your trust. For the same reason you may not trust
in the Lord: you do not know Him. Instead, He is a stranger to you. And because
you do not know Him, you do not trust Him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In either scenario, how can you build trust in the Lord? How can you get to a
place where you trust in the Lord? I reckon that it is not too different with
how you build trust with any other person. First, you must want to get to a
place of trust with a person. If you do not want to trust a person, then you
will not get to a place of trust with that person. So you must want to trust a
person first. The same goes with the Lord. You must want to get to a place of
trust with Him first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you who do not trust people that you do not know, you of course
have to get to know the stranger and build a relationship with them to build
trust in them. And likewise for them to build trust in you. For, as is mentioned
in &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/culture/2019/10/25/tax-collectors-and-sinners&quot;&gt;previous posts&lt;/a&gt;, when you befriend and get to know those whom the rest of
the world thinks should be shunned, you may rise to be in a position of trust
and influence with them such that you may persuade them to turn from their
former ways and instead follow Jesus and become His disciple. But this does not
happen if you do not take the time to befriend and get to know those whom the
world thinks should be shunned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is the same with the Lord. For you to get to a place of trust with the Lord,
you need to build a relationship with Him and get to know Him. Eventually, you
may get to the point in the relationship where the Lord trusts you (and vice
versa) such that you become a person of influence in His life and are able to
persuade Him (and vice versa). Of course, as you have the freedom to choose to
build a relationship and get to know a person, you also have the freedom to
choose to build a relationship and get to know the Lord. The Lord is not going
to force you into a relationship with Him; it is your choice. Of course, the
Lord desires to build a relationship with you and build trust in you. So if you
decide to build a relationship and trust with the Lord, He is ready and willing
to reciprocate. On the other hand, if you do not want to build a relationship
and trust with the Lord, then He will be like a spurned lover. As you build
relationships with other people, the Lord will be waiting by the phone,
metaphorically speaking, hoping that you will change your mind and reach out to
Him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you who used to trust a person but now no longer do, then you have
to want to rebuild your relationship and trust with that person. And if you do
decide to try and rebuild your relationship and trust with a person who had but
lost your trust, a good starting point for that may be to find it in your heart
to forgive them for their transgressions that caused you to stop trusting in
that person. As mentioned in a &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/culture/2019/09/25/retweets-do-not-imply-endorsement&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, you do not have to wait for
the person to apologize or show remorse or show that they have changed before
forgiving them. Instead, you may decide to forgive a person regardless of
whether or not they apologized, sought forgiveness, shown remorse, or shown you
that they have changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lord does not trangress; only us humans do. And yet, people can still lose
trust in the Lord. This could be because they blame the Lord for things that
happened in their life. Or, as it was mentioned in a &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/culture/2019/10/18/the-seed-of-anger&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, it
could be because God’s emissaries turn them away from the Lord. It could also be
because people listen to competing voices. The voices of their family, friends,
and colleagues. And voices in their community, news media, and pop culture.
Voices that contradict the voice or word of God. Voices that persuade them to no
longer trust the voice or word of God. Voices that say to them: God is
irrelevant or unnecessary or dangerous in this day and age. As mentioned in a
&lt;a href=&quot;/posts/life/2020/01/15/scheduled-annihilation&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, those who believe in Jesus ought to be willing to befriend
other people, such as those whom the rest of the world view as wicked, so that
we may be in a position to persuade them. For, if we are not in a position to
influence people, then others will be in a position to influence them. And such
people may influence them to stop trusting in the Lord and turn away from God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That could happen to babies as they grow up. Competing voices may tell them not
to listen to their parent’s advice or guidance. Competing voices may persuade
them to think that they know better than their parents about which direction to
go is best for their life. The same thing could happen to those who believe in
Jesus. People may tell them to not listen to the Lord’s guidance or advice.
And people may persuade them that they know better than the Lord about which
direction to go is best for their life. And because of these competing voices,
people stop following and relying on the Lord. People stop letting the Lord be
their Shepherd. Instead, people rely on and follow the guidance and advice of
the competing voices in their life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I tell you the truth: the Lord knows better than you and your circle of
family, friends, confidantes, et al. about the direction that you should go in
your life. And that is because the guidance and advice that other people give
to you is limited by their knowledge. But, the Lord is all-knowing; He does not
have any blind spots or gaps in His knowledge, so the Lord can give you better
guidance and advice than your coterie of family, friends, confidantes, et al.
It can be similar to when you are trying to get from your current location to
another location. You may decide on particular directions/routes to get to a
particular place, but such choices are based on the limited knowledge that you
and your cohort of family, friends, confidantes, et al. have. And by doing this,
you may see that you need to adjust the directions you followed and make detours
along the way as you come across unexpected roadblocks and obstacles and dead
ends that slow you down or block your path to your destination. The Lord, on the
other hand, is all-seeing. Thus, the Lord knows the best path to take to get you
from your current location to your destination (destiny). The Lord sees if
taking a particular path will lead to a dead end. And the Lord can see if a
particular route has obstacles that would block you from proceeding toward your
destination. Obstacles that would cause you to deviate from your destination
(destiny). Thus, the Lord knows the paths that you should take and the paths
that you should avoid to reach your destiny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not to say that you should never listen or follow the advice of your
clique of family, friends, and confidantes, et al. Of course, their advice may
align with the guidance that you receive from the Lord. But, as mentioned in
&lt;a href=&quot;/posts/life/2018/12/05/did-god-really-say&quot;&gt;previous messages&lt;/a&gt;, when there is a deviation between the Lord’s advice and
the advice of your clan of family, friends, and confidantes, et al., you have a
choice to make: whose advice shall you follow?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course it can be difficult to start trusting and following the guidance and
advice of the Lord when you have always relied upon and trusted the guidance
and advice of your crew of family, friends, and confidantes, et al. That is why
getting to know the Lord is an important step toward getting to a place of trust
with Him. And as you get to know the Lord, also ask for His guidance and advice
with respect to your life and the direction that you should go. You do not have
to stop asking your family, friends, and confidantes, et al. for their guidance
and advice. You can continue to do that. But in addition to asking your family,
friends, and confidantes, et al., you can start to ask the Lord for His guidance
and advice. You can start with small things. You can take baby steps with your
relationship with the Lord. And as He builds your trust in Him, you can start to
trust in Him with the bigger and more important things in your life. And maybe
He eventually becomes a part of your crew. He may become like family to you
(think: God the Father in Heaven; Jesus Christ, your Brother). And He may become
like a friend and confidante to you (think: Jesus Christ, Holy Spirit). But this
does not happen if you do not want to build a relationship with the Lord and get
to know Him and get to a place of trust with Him, so decide today whether or not
you want the Lord to become a part of your circle of trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God bless.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Life" /><category term="trust" /><category term="circle" /><category term="clan" /><category term="clique" /><category term="cohort" /><category term="coterie" /><category term="crew" /><summary type="html">In the previous message, it was suggested that you should let the Lord be your Shepherd. For, when you do that, you shall not lack anything in any sphere of your life since the Lord shall give you more than enough for your needs in all aspects of your life. But it can be hard to let someone be your guide in life if you do not trust that person. Likewise, if you do not trust a person—whether it be the Lord or someone else—it can be hard to listen to their advice let alone follow their guidance. For, if you don’t trust a person, you may not believe that they have your best interests at heart nor may you think that they know which direction to go would be best for your life.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/45976390/77794328-1030af80-7042-11ea-8a43-d75dc0ade7a2.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/45976390/77794328-1030af80-7042-11ea-8a43-d75dc0ade7a2.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Lord Is My Shepherd</title><link href="https://www.orchard.cc/posts/life/2020/02/19/the-lord-is-my-shepherd" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Lord Is My Shepherd" /><published>2020-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://www.orchard.cc/posts/life/2020/02/19/the-lord-is-my-shepherd</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.orchard.cc/posts/life/2020/02/19/the-lord-is-my-shepherd">&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The Lord is my shepherd; I shall not want.
&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 23:1 NKJV&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The Lord is my shepherd, I lack nothing.
&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 23:1 NIV&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Because the Lord is my Shepherd, I have everything I need!
&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 23:1 TLB&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lord is my shepherd; I shall not want. In other words, when the Lord is your
shepherd, you shall not lack anything; instead, you shall have everything that
you need. (Note that it says that you shall have everything that you &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt;, and
not everything that you &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt;.) Now, the things that you shall not lack is not
limited to worldly things such as money; jobs or businesses; private homes,
cars, and jets; and the like. No! This lack is referring to every area of your
life. For, there are a multitude of people who do not lack such worldly things,
yet feel empty inside because they lack in other areas of their lives such as:
mental and physical health; love, joy, peace, and other emotional needs; purpose
and fulfillment; and the like. But when the Lord is your shepherd, you shall not
lack in any aspect of your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, this is not to say that you will be shielded from challenges and
difficulties when the Lord is your shepherd. For, as King David (the author)
says: Even though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I fear no
evil, for You are with me; Your rod and Your staff, they comfort me (Psalm 23:4
NASB). In his journey in life, King David walked through the valley of the
shadow of death. Or, in other words, King David experienced challenges and
difficulties in his journey in life. But, as mentioned in &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/culture/2018/11/28/you-are-not-alone&quot;&gt;previous message&lt;/a&gt;,
the Lord is always with you. And the Lord is there for you in the midst of the
challenges or difficulties that you are facing. The Lord is there to meet your
needs whilst amidst your challenges or difficulties. The Lord gives you peace so
that you do not fear. The Lord gives you comfort so that you are not overcome
with anxiety and stress whilst amidst your challenges or difficulties. The Lord
gives you strength so that you are not overpowered by your challenges and
difficulties. And the Lord gives you wisdom and guidance so that you may get
through your challenges and difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, King David said: You prepare a feast for me in the presence of my
enemies. You honor me by anointing my head with oil. My cup overflows with
blessings (Psalm 23:5 NLT). Now, as a follower of the Lord your Shepherd, the
people of this world may hate on you or condemn you because they disagree with
you and your beliefs. Such people may cause challenges or difficulties in your
life. But when the Lord is your Shepherd, He shall prepare a feast for you in
the presence of your enemies. In other words, your enemies shall see that the
Lord is with you. Likewise, your enemies will see that the Lord has honored your
faith in Him. And your enemies will see that the Lord has abundantly blessed you
such that you do not lack in any aspect of your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the Lord is not your Shepherd, then someone or something else is your
shepherd. If the Lord is not the One who leads and guides you in your journey in
life, then it is someone or something else who leads and guides you in your
journey in life. This may be illustrated in a particular story in King David’s
life—the story of King David and a woman named Bathsheba, which you may read
in chapters eleven and twelve in The Second Book of Samuel. But for the purposes
of this post, here is a brief summary of that story: One day, King David saw a
woman bathing from the roof of his home. Intrigued, David inquired about her;
and he found out that she (Bathsheba) is the daughter of a man named Eliam and
the wife of a man named Uriah. Undeterred, she sent messengers to bring her to
him so that he may lay with her. This unbalanced power dynamic between the man
(David) and the woman (Bathsheba) may be familiar to those who have had similar
experiences or read similar stories in this day and age. Experiences and stories
that birthed the #MeToo movement. However, as mentioned in &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/culture/2019/09/25/retweets-do-not-imply-endorsement&quot;&gt;previous posts&lt;/a&gt;,
while the Lord will always love you, He may not agree with your action. The Lord
also did not agree with David’s actions, as you will see later. King David’s
action resulted in Bathsheba becoming pregnant. When he found out that she was
with child, he came up with a plan to hide his indiscretion. When that plan
failed, David came up with another plan to get her husband intentionally killed
in the battlefield. This plan succeeded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, in this particular instance, was the Lord David’s Shepherd? Was King David
following the lead and guidance of the Lord when he chose to lay with Bathsheba,
and subsequently chose to have her husband killed in the battlefield? No, he was
not. The Lord was not his Shepherd in this instance. So who was King David’s
shepherd in this instance? His own desire. For, each one is tempted when he is
drawn away by his own desires and enticed. Then, when desire has conceived, it
gives birth to sin; and sin, when it is full-grown, brings forth death (James
1:14-15 NKJV). In other words, temptation is the pull of man’s own evil thoughts
and wishes. These evil thoughts lead to evil actions and afterwards to the death
penalty from God (James 1:14-15 TLB). David was enticed by the woman that he saw
from the roof of his home; David desired her. David acted upon his desire; it
birthed sin and brought forth death. In this instance, David was lead by his own
desires instead of the Lord. But if the Lord was his Shepherd in this instance,
then he would not have been lead to sin. For the Lord does not lead you to sin;
rather, He leads you in the paths of righteousness For His name’s sake (Psalm
23:3 NKJV).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this way, David is not too different from Adam and Eve. As mentioned in a
&lt;a href=&quot;/posts/life/2018/12/05/did-god-really-say&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, Adam and Eve worked in the garden of Eden; they were allowed
to eat of the fruit of every tree in the garden of Eden except for the fruit
from the tree of the knowledge of good and evil. One day, they were enticed to
eat fruit from that tree. The woman saw that the tree had fruit that was good to
eat, nice to look at, and desirable for making someone wise. So she took some of
the fruit and ate it. She also gave some to her husband, who was with her, and
he ate it (Genesis 3:6 GW). The woman desired the fruit of the tree. Therefore,
like King David, the woman acted upon that desire; and it birthed sin, which
brought forth death. The Lord was not Adam and Eve’s shepherd in this instance;
instead, they were lead and guided by their own desires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I gave your master’s house to you, and your master’s wives into your arms. I
gave you all Israel and Judah. And if all this had been too little, I would have
given you even more. &lt;cite&gt;2 Samuel 12:8 NIV&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in that previous post, Adam and Eve ate of the fruit from the tree
of the knowledge of good and evil because they were unsatisfied with what the
Lord had already given them, namely the fruit of every other tree in the garden
of Eden. And because of this dissatisfaction, they desired more. Likewise, King
David was unsatisfied with all that the Lord had already given him. And because
of his dissatisfaction, David desired more. This desire for more was not because
the Lord did not give David enough such that he was lacking in some area of his
life. The Lord gave David more than enough. The Lord gave David his master’s
house and wives. The Lord also gave David all of Israel and Judah. And if what
the Lord had given him was too little, then the Lord would have given him even
more so that he has enough for all his needs. Thus, King David’s desire for more
was born from his dissatisfaction with what the Lord had already given him, and
not because the Lord did not give him enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like Adam and Eve and David, people of this world may be dissatisfied with what
they have. Because of this dissatisfaction, they desire more even though they
have more than enough for their needs; so the people of this world act upon this
desire for more. You may have noticed this, as there has been an increased
frequency of such stories over the last couple of years. Stories of men (the
married and unmarried variety) in a plethora of industries (such as the media,
entertainment, sports, government, finance, tech, religious, non-profit, and the
like) acting upon their desire to be with women who are not their wives. Women
such as journalists, actresses, gymnasts, porn stars, analysts and managers,
engineers, church members, activists and volunteers, and the like. Women who had
not consented to such actions by those men. Women who were taken advantage of by
men in positions of power and influence. Women who felt like they had no choice
but to begrudgingly accept such behaviour from men lest they be fired or denied
future opportunities in the business or industry. In these cases, the men may be
like David and the woman like Bathsheba, who may have felt like she had no
choice but to partake in what David wanted to do with her because of the
unbalanced power dynamic between them and the consequence or retaliation that
could arise if she did not partake in what he wanted to do with her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned earlier, even though the Lord shall always love you, the Lord does
not always endorse or agree with your actions because those actions birth sin
and bring forth death (or consequences). Those consequences may include: death
of your job or business; death of your reputation; death of your marriage; death
of harmony with your friends, family, church community, colleagues, and social
groups; and the like. The Lord did not agree with David’s action. In fact, the
Lord was displeased with what David had done (2 Samuel 11:27 NLT) since the
thing that David had done was evil in the sight of the Lord (2 Samuel 11:27
NASB). Likewise, the thing that David had done birthed sin and brought forth
death (or consequences). Those consequences included: death of the child that he
conceived with the woman, Bathsheba; death of relationship with his other wives;
and death of harmony in his household.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So: Whom shall you choose to be your shepherd? Shall you choose the Lord as your
Shepherd? Or shall you choose to be lead by your own desires? I suggest for you
to let the Lord be your Shepherd rather than be lead by your own desires. If you
have been letting your own desires lead and guide your actions in life, it is
not too late to change course. It is not too late to start letting the Lord lead
and guide your actions in life. It is not too late to start letting the Lord be
your Shepherd in life. For, even though the Lord did not endorse or agree with
David’s actions, the Lord forgave David. Likewise, even though the Lord did not
endorse or agree with the actions of the men who were exposed in the #MeToo era,
the Lord is willing to forgive those people. Whilst the people of this world may
not be willing to forgive those caught in the #MeToo era, the Lord is willing to
forgive them. The Lord is also willing to give those people a second chance in
life. And the Lord is willing to conceive new life to that which died because of
their actions. If their job or business died because of their action, then the
Lord is willing to conceive a new job for them. Likewise, if their friendships
died because of their action, the Lord is willing to conceive new friends for
them. And If their church died because of their action, then the Lord is willing
to conceive a new church for them. Thus, if you currently find that some aspects
of your life are dead because you chose to follow the lead of your own desire,
then you too may have a new life by choosing to instead follow the lead/guidance
of the Lord. A life wherein all of your needs are met such that you shall not
lack anything in any aspect of your life. Just believe. And let the Lord be your
Shepherd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God bless.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Life" /><category term="Me Too" /><summary type="html">The Lord is my shepherd; I shall not want. Psalm 23:1 NKJV The Lord is my shepherd, I lack nothing. Psalm 23:1 NIV Because the Lord is my Shepherd, I have everything I need! Psalm 23:1 TLB</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/45976390/74894523-3b4a2400-535d-11ea-982c-65db27cbb8ee.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/45976390/74894523-3b4a2400-535d-11ea-982c-65db27cbb8ee.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>